CHUKWU UCHENNA

I am a passionate Front-End developer with 2 years of experience in developing and implementing innovative software solutions. I am dedicated to making the world a better place using the power of emerging Technologies, and to delivering software solutions that drive business success

Xander lodge
Agbani, Enugu state
09073508329
uchechukwu7814@gmail.com
https://github.com/Yhucee14
https://my-portfolio-yhucee14.vercel.app/

EXPERIENCE

Software Developer Intern at SideHustle

LOCATION: Oyo state, Nigeria

March 2022 - April 2022

At SideHustle I worked remotely and I was exposed to React for Web Development.

Software Developer Intern at ZuriHNG

LOCATION: Lagos State, Nigeria

October 2022 - November 2022

At Zuri I worked remotely and extensively improved my React skills by making use of Material UI to build a landing page displaying my personal page.

Software Developer Intern at Preggify

LOCATION: Lagos state, Nigeria @ www.preggify.com

June 2023 - February 2024

At Preggify I worked with the team to build Preggify.com

Software Developer/IT Consultant at Atrizult

LOCATION: Enugu state, Nigeria

December 2023 - February 2024

AtAtrizult , I worked with the team using Agile methodology to satisfy clients business requirements using Reactjs, Typescript, Scss and various software development processes. As a consultant I was also tasked with mentoring other trainees.

Hobbies

Coding

Reading

Playing Football

Playing Games

Music

SKILLS

 ${\tt TECHNICAL\ SKILLS: HTML, CSS,}$

Javascript, Git.

 ${\bf FRAMEWORKS/LIBRARIES: React,}$

Next, Tailwind, Material UI.

REFEREE

Available on request.

EDUCATION

Qua Iboe Church Comprehensive , Akwa Ibom, Nigeria — SSCE

September 2012 - September 2018

LOCATION: Atabong, Eket, Akwa Ibom State, Nigeria.

Enugu State University Of Science And Technology, Enugu, Nigeria — BSc Computer Engineering (Undergraduate)

October 2019 - October 2024

LOCATION: Agbani, Enugu State, Nigeria

PROJECTS

A weather forecast application that provides information on the weather conditions of various areas using Rapid Api.

Built a login/register form with forgot password feature that sends a reset password message to your Email using Firebase for data storage and authentication.

Built a simple todo app

Built a movie discovery web application that allows users to search for movies, view details about them, and save their favorite movies using data from the TMDB API.

Collaborated with the team to build Preggify's website.

Built my Personal Portfolio Website using Nextjs, Tailwind CSS and Framer Motion.

Built a website for the annual Tech Starters Conference hackathon and CTF.